An Inventory of the Elbridge Durbrow papers, 1926-1996
Hoover Institution Archives
- Outlines by Durbrow, 1981, undated (Box 28)
  - "Soviet Methods of Operation in Their Long-range Drive to Attain World Hegemony and the Role of Terrorism Therein,", 1981 (Box 28)
  - "Détente - How Realistic?", undated (Box 28)
- Drafts by Durbrow, 1973, 1976-1977, undated (Box 28)
  - "A New U.S. Strategy for Peace and Freedom,", 1977 (Box 28)
  - "Implementation of the 1969 'Popular Unity' Formula in Iceland, Norway, France, Italy and Spain,", undated (Box 28)
  - "Hot War, Cold War, and Détente,", undated (Box 28)
  - "Operation 'Dezinformatsia',", undated (Box 28)
  - "Wars of National Liberation,", undated (Box 28)
  - "Laos and Vietnam ? The Same War,", undated (Box 28)
  - "Center Left-Wing Coalition Government?", undated (Box 28)
  - "The Unseen Revolution,", 1976 (Box 28)
  - "The Kremlin European Plans for 1976,", undated (Box 28)
  - "Brezhnev: The Man and the Myth,", 1973 (Box 28)
- Speech outlines by Durbrow, 1972, undated (Box 28)
  - "Communist Plans for Victory,", 1972 (Box 28)
  - "The Growing Communist Threat,", undated (Box 28)
- Writings by Durbrow, 1982, undated (Box 28)
  - "Random Comments on Recent Developments,", 1982 (Box 28)
  - "Taiwan Endangered,", undated (Box 28)
  - "The Quiet World Revolution,", undated (Box 28)
  - "Operation 'Dezinformatsia,'", undated (Box 28)
- Clippings, 1971-1976. (Box 29)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1968, 1971-1975. (Box 29)
- International press summaries, 1975-1976 (Box 29)
- Correspondence, 1972, 1974-1975. (Box 29)
- Memorandum, 1974 (Box 29)
- U.S. government report and press release, 1971-1972 (Box 29)
- AFL-CIO Executive Council statement, 1973 (Box 29)
- Soviet Constitution Rights, excerpt photocopy, undated (Box 29)
- "Solzhenitsyn," CBS News Special transcript, 1974 (Box 29)
- "Lest We Forget," draft by Durbrow, 1968 (Box 29)
- "Communist Plans for Victory" by Durbrow, speech outline, 1972 (Box 29)
- "Soviet Methods of Operation in Their Long-Range Drive to Attain World Hegemony and the Role of Terrorism Therein," by Durbrow, outline, 1981 (Box 29)
- "The Soviet Dissident Movement as a Tool of Communist Aggression Against the Back," by Natalie Grant, 1975 (Box 29)
- "TV and National Defense: An Analysis of CBS News, 1972-1973," by Institute for American Strategy, circa 1973 (Box 29)
- Clippings, 1970-1973, 1975-1976 (Box 30)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1972, 1976 (Box 30)
- International press summaries, 1972, 1976 (Box 30)
- Memorandum, 1976 (Box 30)
- "Solzhenitsyn," CBS News Special transcript, 1974 (Box 30)
- Clippings relating to Vietnam and the 24th Congress of the Communist Party, 1970-1974, 1976 (Box 31)
- Printed material, 1971, 1973-1975 (Box 31)
- International press summaries, 1971, 1973, 1975-1976 (Box 31)
- Correspondence photocopies, 1974 (Box 31)
- Memoranda, 1973, circa 1974. (Box 31)
- U.S. government reports and press releases, 1973-1974 (Box 31)
- American Conservative seminar documents, 1974 (Box 31)
- Washington Report of the Air broadcasts, transcript, 1974-1975 (Box 31)
- Ambassador Martin speech, 1974 (Box 31)
- CBS Evening News with Walter Cronkite, transcript, 1974 (Box 31)
- NBC Today Show interview with Robert C. Ransom and George W. Webber, transcript, 1974 (Box 31)
- Document on subjects of interest related to Vietnam fact finding trip to Vietnam, circa 1974 (Box 31)
- Ambassador Graham Martin address to the Republic of Vietnam Committee on International Relations, 1976 (Box 31)
- Drafts by Durbrow, undated (Box 31)
  - "The 24th Soviet Communist Party Congress ? An Assessment,", undated (Box 31)
  - "Vietnam Revisited," by Durbrow, undated (Box 31)
- "Communist Plans for Victory," by Durbrow, outline, undated (Box 31)
- The Communist Party of the Soviet Union speech delivered by Leonid Brezhnev, report photocopy, 1971 (Box 31)
- "Response to Ambassador Graham A. Martin's cable" by David K. Shipler, photocopy, 1974 (Box 31)
- "1973 and Beyond," by Durbrow (Box 31)
- "The Soviet Role in North Vietnam's Offensive," unknown author, undated (Box 31)
- Clippings relating to Vietnam, 1960, 1969-1971, 1974-1975. (Box 32)
- Printed material, 1969, 1974 (Box 32)
- International press summaries, 1974 (Box 32)
- Correspondence, 1969, 1974 (Box 32)
- Memorandum, 1974 (Box 32)
- U.S. government reports and press release, 1967, 1969-1970, 1973 (Box 32)
- Washington Report of the Air broadcasts, transcript, 1974 (Box 32)
- Document highlighting visit to Vietnam based on fact finding trip by Durbrow, 1974 (Box 32)
- "U.S. Policy in Vietnam," by Durbrow, speech outline, undated (Box 32)
- Ambassador Graham Martin remarks before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1974 (Box 32)
- The Communist and Workers' Party meeting report, 1969 (Box 32)
- Nikita Khrushchev speech, outline, 1966 (Box 32)
- CBS Evening News with Walter Cronkite, excerpt, 1974 (Box 32)
- "Agreement on Ending the War and Restoring Peace in Vietnam," photocopy, 1973 (Box 32)
- "The Declaration of Renewed Cold War," by Durbrow, undated (Box 32)
- "Declaration of Renewed Cold War, 1967, 1969,", undated (Box 32)
- "Renewed Cold War - Wars on National Liberation," by Durbrow, undated (Box 32)
- Clippings relating to Vietnam, 1971, 1973-1975 (Box 33)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1974-1976 (Box 33)
- International press summaries, 1975 (Box 33)
- Correspondence, 1971, 1974-1975. (Box 33)
- Memoranda, 1975, undated (Box 33)
- U.S. government report and press release, 1973, 1974 (Box 33)
- NBC News Special Report, transcript, 1971 (Box 33)
- Notes relating to subjects of interest for Vietnam fact finding trip, circa 1974 (Box 33)
- Washington Report of the Air broadcast, transcript, 1971 (Box 33)
- Secretary of Defense Schlesinger's news conference, 1975 (Box 33)
- AFL-CIO Executive Council statement on Indochina, 1975 (Box 33)
- "Plight of our Vietnamese Friends," by Durbrow, 1975 (Box 33)
- "Agreement on Ending the War and Restoring Peace in Vietnam," photocopy, 1973 (Box 33)
- "The Pentagon Papers and Other News," by Arthur G.B. Metcalf, circa 1971 (Box 33)
- "The Threat," by Dr. Léon Gouré, photocopy, 1974 (Box 33)
- Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 34)
- Printed material, 1965-1967, 1971, undated (Box 34)
- U.S. government reports and press releases, 1963-1967, 1969 (Box 34)
- Assistant Secretary for Far Eastern Affairs statement before the House Appropriation Committee, 1960 (Box 34)
- Deputy Under Secretary of State, Foy D. Kohler address to the Air War College Class of 1968 (Box 34)
- Outlines by Durbrow, undated (Box 34)
  - "NATO Today,", undated (Box 34)
  - "NATO a Political Organization,", undated (Box 34)
  - "The Ambassador and the Country Team,", undated (Box 34)
- Assistant Chief of European Division, Paul Culbertson statement, 1967 (Box 34)
- Speech outlines by Durbrow, 1966, 1968, 1970, undated (Box 34)
  - "Comments on General Beaufre's Lecture,", undated (Box 34)
  - "West Europe and NATO,", undated (Box 34)
  - "Foreign Policy,", 1968 (Box 34)
  - "Problems of Negotiating with Communists,", undated (Box 34)
  - "U.S. Foreign Policy in the Fart East,", 1966 (Box 34)
  - "America Answers the Challenge of Communism" delivered to the University of Southern Mississippi, 1966 (Box 34)
  - "The New Country Team Operations in Washington,", 1970 (Box 34)
- "Economic independence and Free Vietnam" by Durbrow, undated (Box 34)
- "The Changing Role of the UN," by Durbrow, 1967 (Box 34)
- "U.S. Policy and the New Europe," by Frank Church, undated (Box 34)
- Clippings relating to Vietnam and the Pentagon papers, 1962-1963, 1965-1967, 1969, 1972-1973. (Box 35)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1965-1966 (Box 35)
- U.S. government reports and press releases, 1965-1966 (Box 35)
- President Johnson remarks on V-E Day anniversary, undated (Box 35)
- "U.S. Policy in Vietnam," by Durbrow, speech outline, undated (Box 35)
- "Should Ellsberg Be Prosecuted?" by Durbrow, outline, undated (Box 35)
- "The Divided Buddhists of South Vietnam," by Denis Warner, circa 1966 (Box 35)
- Clippings relating to Vietnam, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 36)
- U.S. government reports, 1969 (Box 36)
- Ambassador W. E. Colby opening statement at the Senate Foreign Relations Committee Hearings on Vietnam, 1970 (Box 36)
- Clippings relating to Vietnam, 1968-1969 (Box 37)
- Printed material, 1968 (Box 37)
- International press summaries, 1969 (Box 37)
- U.S. government reports, 1968 (Box 37)
- "Resolution on Vietnam" and Vietnam Commission report from the World Peace Assembly, 1969 (Box 37)
- ABC News' Issues and Answers broadcast with Senator J. William Fulbright, transcript, 1969 (Box 37)
- Viet Cong's 10-Point Proposal in Paris, unofficial translation, 1969 (Box 37)
- President Johnson speech of March 31, 1968, media analysis (Box 37)
- Clippings relating to Vietnam, 1968-1969, 1972-1974 (Box 38)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1964, 1969 (Box 38)
- Correspondence, 1972 (Box 38)
- U.S. government reports, 1972 (Box 38)
- "A Thousand Days: John F. Kennedy in the White House," by Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr., excerpts, 1965 (Box 38)
- "The Declaration of Renewed Cold War," draft by Durbrow, 1969 (Box 38)
- Clippings relating to Vietnam, 1967-1970, 1973-1979 (Box 39)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1966, 1972, 1974, 1976-1977 (Box 39)
- Correspondence, 1974 (Box 39)
- U.S. government reports, 1959, 1973-1974. (Box 39)
- Notes relating to subjects of interest for Vietnam fact finding trip, circa 1974 (Box 39)
- CBS Radio First Line, transcript, 1974 (Box 39)
- The NBC Today Show with Robert C. Ransom and George W. Webber, transcript, 1974 (Box 39)
- Washington Report of the Air broadcasts, transcript, 1974 (Box 39)
- Ambassador Martin speech delivered at an embassy ceremony, 1974 (Box 39)
- Highlights of visit to Vietnam by Durbrow based on fact finding trip, 1974 (Box 39)
- Vietnam fact-finding itinerary and schedule, 1974 (Box 39)
- Betrayal in Vietnam by Louis A. Fanning, excerpts, 1976 (Box 39)
- "Response to Ambassador Graham A. Martin's cable," by David K. Shipler, photocopy, 1974 (Box 39)
- "Not in Vain," based on an independent fact-finding mission to South Vietnam by Durbrow, 1974 (Box 39)
- "Hanoi's Intensified Aggression - 1959," by Durbrow, 1968 (Box 39)
- Clippings, 1961, 1968-1969, 1971 (Box 39)
- Printed material, 1967-1969, 1971 (Box 39)
- Correspondence, 1971, 1995 (Box 39)
- Memoranda, 1967 Includes photocopies (Box 39)
- U.S. government reports, 1949, 1962, 1964-1967, undated. (Box 39)
- Memoir, draft, circa 1995 (Box 39)
  Includes diskette
- "Undiplomatic History, The Stealthful Soviet Saga," draft by Durbrow, circa 1995 (Box 39)
- Eisenhower's remarks at the Governor's conference, excerpts, 1953 (Box 39)
- Communiqué issued by the Unified Buddhist Association of Vietnam, April 12, 1965 (Box 39)
- Leonard C. Meeker address to the Harvard International Law Club, 1966 (Box 39)
- Secretary Dean Rusk address before the American-Japan Society and the American Chamber of Commerce, 1964 (Box 39)
- Secretary Dean Rusk replies to questions from various television shows and news conferences, excepts, 1964-1968 (Box 39)
- "Hanoi's About Face - 1959," draft by Durbrow, undated (Box 39)
- "Development in Vietnam, 1954-1966," which evolved in to "Hanoi's About Face," outline, undated (Box 39)
- "Secretary's Statement on President John F. Kennedy for Passman Committee," by unknown author, draft, 1966 (Box 39)
- "U.S. Policy/Aid for Indo-China 1949-1954: Selected Chronology," by Durbrow, undated (Box 39)
- Clippings relating to research used for memoirs, 1986-1988 (Box 41)
- "The Basic, Unheralded Reasons for the Failure of Leninism," by Durbrow, 1990 (Box 41)
  Encompasses three versions from April, May and July
- "Un-Diplomatic History," memoir partial draft, August 12, 1992 (Box 41)
- "Undiplomatic History: The Sordid Soviet Saga," memoir draft, August 15, 1994 (Box 41)
- "Undiplomatic History: The Stealthful Soviet Saga," memoir working title, September, 1995 (Box 41)
- "The Stealthful Soviet Century" memoir working title, July 9, 1996 (Box 41)
- Clippings relating to Soviet Union disinformation tactics, 1985-1988 (Box 42)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1974, 1986-1987 (Box 42)
- U.S. government reports, 1986 (Box 42)
- Clippings relating to the Soviet Union and NATO, 1980, 1985-1989 (Box 43)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1987-1989 (Box 43)
- U.S. government reports, 1987 (Box 43)
- Clippings, 1981-1982, 1987-1989 (Box 44)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1981, 1987-1988 (Box 44)
- International press summaries, 1980 (Box 44)
- U.S. government reports, 1966 (Box 44)
- BBC Reith Lecture series episode "Russia, The Atom, and the West" hosted by George Kennan, transcript, 1957 (Box 44)
- Sub Rosa: The CIA and the Uses of Intelligence by Peer de Silva, excerpt photocopies, 1978 (Box 44)
- Clippings, 1972, 1979-1980, 1984-1985, undated (Box 45)
- Printed material, 1969, 1971-1972, 1975, 1977, 1980-1981, 1983-1985 (Box 45)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1963, 1972, 1974, 1981-1982, 1984-1985. (Box 45)
- International press summaries, 1984 (Box 45)
- U.S. government reports, 1967, undated (Box 45)
- A. Golitsyn statement to participants at the conference on "Disinformation in the Modern World,", 1984 (Box 45)
- U.S. - Chinese Communiqué, 1972 (Box 45)
- Durbrow oral history interview by John T. Mason Jr., for the Columbia University Oral History project, transcripts, 1981 (Box 45)
- The Republican Womens' and St. Paul panel meeting speech notes, 1983-1984 (Box 45)
- National War College (NWC) European trip group biographies and schedules, 1974 (Box 45)
- Biographical information for British speakers during the NWC European trip, 1974 (Box 45)
- "Kremlin's Best Postwar Harvest," from Welt am Sonntag by Ernest J. Cramer, 1972 (Box 45)
  Article translated into English
- "Yesterday the Suez Canal and Tomorrow the Elbe..." by Axel Springer 1974. Article translated into English (Box 45)
- The Strange Alliance: The Story of Our Efforts at Wartime Co-Operation with Russia by John R. Deane, excerpts, undated (Box 45)
- "Fighting Against Disinformation," by Constantin Melnik, 1984 (Box 45)
- "Taiwan Endangered," by Durbrow, undated (Box 45)
- "A Brief Perspective of the National War College,", undated (Box 45)
- Clippings, 1956, 1967, 1975, 1978-1979, 1984-1990 (Box 46)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1969, 1975, 1984-1986, 1988, 1990, undated (Box 46)
- U.S. government reports and press releases, 1954, 1956, 1967, 1976, 1987 (Box 46)
- Correspondence, 1957, 1967-1971, 1977, 1985, 1987 (Box 46)
  Includes personal letters relating to niece, Connie Kellam, and Presidents Truman and Eisenhower. Includes photocopies
- Photograph at a Loy Henderson event, 1977 (Box 46)
- Gorbachev's speech at the Great October Socialist Revolution (GOSR) meeting, 1987 (Box 46)
- Loy W. Henderson's memoirs, undated (Box 46)
- Documents relating to Henderson's memoirs, 1954-1955, undated (Box 46)
- Eulogy given by Durbrow at Henderson's memorial service, 1986 (Box 46)
- A. Golitsyn statement to the participants at the conference on "Disinformation in the Modern World,", 1984 (Box 46)
- "Fighting Against Disinformation," by Constantin Melnik, undated (Box 46)
- Clippings, 1972-1975, 1979, 1981-1985, 1987 (Box 47)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1943, 1961, 1965, 1977, 1979-1984 (Box 47)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1973, 1980, 1982-1984 (Box 47)
- Memoranda photocopies, 1982, 1983 (Box 47)
- International press summaries, 1973, 1981 (Box 47)
- U.S. government reports, 1956, 1962, 1972-1973, 1982-1983, 1985 (Box 47)
- Nikita Kruschev speech "For New Victories of the World Communist Movement,", 1961 (Box 47)
- Leonid Brezhnev report to the Communist Party of the Soviet Union (CPSU), 1976 (Box 47)
- "Soviet Methods of Operation in Their Long-range Drive to Attain World Hegemony and the Role of Terrorism Therein," by Durbrow, outline, 1981 (Box 47)
- Director of the FBI, William H. Webster, statement before the Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism U.S. Senate, 1982 (Box 47)
- Senator Jeremiah Denton' opening statement before the Subcommittee on Security and Terrorism, 1982 (Box 47)
- "Decree of Soviet Power," September 5, 1918, 1982 (Box 47)
  Photocopy of English translation
- "Decree on Red Terror" photocopy, September 5, 1918, 1918 (Box 47)
- "Communist Post Vietnam Cease-Fire Plans," by Durbrow, lecture outline, undated (Box 47)
- "The Khrushchev Doctrine and El Salvador or (El Salvador - Another War of National Liberation)," by Durbrow, 1983 (Box 47)
- "El Salvador and Vietnam...Continued," by Durbrow, 1984 (Box 47)
- "Why the Lebanon Dilemma," by Durbrow, 1984 (Box 47)
- Clippings, 1947, 1970, 1974-1975, 1978-1982 (Box 48)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1970-1972, 1974, 1976-1978, 1979-1981 (Box 48)
- Correspondence, 1946-1947, 1949, 1953, 1965-1966, 1968, 1970, 1976, 1978, 1982-1983, undated. (Box 48)
  Includes letter from Manlio Brosio, 4th Secretary General of NATO
- Memorabilia, 1945, 1947, 1960, 1962, 1965-1966, 1975, undated. (Box 48)
  Includes Foreign Service certificates signed by Franklin D. Roosevelt, Adolf Berle, Harry S. Truman and Joseph Grew
- U.S. government reports, 1970, 1978, 1981-1982. (Box 48)
- The Berlin Agreement photocopy, 1972 (Box 48)
- Durbrow interview for the Lyndon B. Johnson oral history project, transcript, 1981 (Box 48)
- SALT II Agreement photocopy, 1979 (Box 48)
- Technological Terrorism by Richard Charles Clark, excerpt photocopies, 1980 (Box 48)
- Excerpts from Speeches by Joseph Stalin and V. M. Molotov, delivered at election meetings in Moscow in February, 1946, photocopy (Box 48)
- Soviet Union Ambassador to France S. V. Chervonenko's address given to the International Diplomatic Academy, 1980 (Box 48)
- The 20th Congress of the Communist Party of The Soviet Union review report, 1956 (Box 48)
- Drafts by Durbrow, circa 1970, 1977 (Box 48)
  - "A New U.S. Strategy for Peace and Freedom,", 1977 (Box 48)
  - "Détente's Triple Threat,", 1977 (Box 48)
  - "The Bonn-Moscow Treaty, a Good or Bad Omen?", circa 1970 (Box 48)
- "National Composition of the Population of the Soviet Union as a Whole," unknown author, 1980 (Box 48)
- Clippings, 1956, 1974, 1976, 1977-1983 (Box 49)
- New York Times newspapers on the moon landing, walk and return, 1969 (Box 49)
- Correspondence, 1956, 1976-1983 (Box 49)
- Memorandum photocopy, 1979 (Box 49)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1961, 1969, 1974, 1978, 1980-1983. (Box 49)
- International press summaries, 1947, 1955-1957, 1977-1980. (Box 49)
- U.S. government reports, 1961, 1969, 1978 (Box 49)
- KGB General Yevgenii Petrovich Pitovranov, background report photocopy, undated (Box 49)
- "International Communist Front Organizations," photocopy, undated (Box 49)
- Politburo of the CPSU Central Committee members, 1977 (Box 49)
- SALT II Agreement photocopy, 1979 (Box 49)
- Iurii Vladimirovich Andropov biographical data photocopy, 1981 (Box 49)
- Sub Rosa: The CIA and the Uses of Intelligence by Peer de Silva, excerpt photocopies, 1978 (Box 49)
- 60 Minutes broadcast with Vladimir Bukovsky, transcript, 1977 (Box 49)
- Gerald R. Ford's speech, "The Canopy of Tyranny," delivered to Westminster College, 1977 (Box 49)
- George Kennan speech on receiving the Albert Einstein Peace Prize, 1981 (Box 49)
- Drafts by Durbrow, 1947, 1980, 1982, undated. (Box 49)
  - "Soviet Indirect Aggression: Motives and Methods,", 1982 (Box 49)
  - "Wrong Ambassador at the Wrong Time,", undated (Box 49)
  - "The International Policy of the Soviet Union in the Second Year of Peace,", 1947 (Box 49)
  - "Dezinformatsia: Mission Accomplished" or "Confusion Unlimited,", undated (Box 49)
  - "Afghanistan,", 1980 (Box 49)
  - "El Salvador ? Another Soviet War of National Liberation,", 1983 (Box 49)
- "Russia - Seven Years Later," by George Kennan, 1944 (Box 49)
- Clippings, 1944, 1967, 1972-1982 (Box 50)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1970-1971, 1974-1975, 1977-1980, 1982-1983 (Box 50)
- U.S. government reports and press releases, 1967, 1969, 1978, 1981 (Box 50)
- International press summaries, 1969, 1971-1974, 1977-1981 (Box 50)
- Memorandum from the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, undated (Box 50)
- A Diplomatic History of the American People, excerpt photocopy, 1974 (Box 50)
- American Diplomacy on Monroe Doctrine, excerpt photocopies, 1923 (Box 50)
- Leonid Brezhnev report to the 24th CPSU Congress, excerpts, 1971 (Box 50)
- Sir James Goldsmith statement to the Media Committee of the Conservative Party, House of Commons, photocopy, January 21, 1981 (Box 50)
- "Solzhenitsyn," CBS News Special broadcast transcript, 1974 (Box 50)
- Shevchenko interview, transcript, undated (Box 50)
- Senator Daniel P. Moynihan statement before the House Committee on Foreign Affairs Subcommittee on International Organizations, March 22, 1979 (Box 50)
- John Hart testimony at the House Assassinations hearings, 1978 (Box 50)
- Admiral Stansfield Turner, Director of the CIA, address given to the Washington Institute of Foreign Affairs, January 25, 1978 (Box 50)
- Admiral Stansfield Turner, Director of the CIA, address given to national conference of Bar Presidents, August 10, 1979 (Box 50)
- Admiral Stansfield Turner, Director of the CIA, address given before the Subcommittee on Intelligence and Rights of Americans Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, 1977 (Box 50)
- Alcksandr Y. Bovin interview, "A Soviet View of Détente," excerpts, 1976 (Box 50)
- Jay Lovestone's remarks on "The Ides of March,", 1978 (Box 50)
- "Our 'Zero Security' Society," by Senator Orrin G. Hatch, undated (Box 50)
- "Hot War, Cold War, and Détente - All Pay Well for the Kremlin," by Durbrow, undated (Box 50)
- "El Salvador - Another Soviet War of National Liberation," draft by Durbrow, 1980 (Box 50)
- Clippings, 1984, 1986-1988 (Box 51)
- Printed material and photocopies, 1984, 1986-1988 (Box 51)
- Correspondence, 1981, 1984-1985. (Box 51)
- U.S. government report, 1956, 1960, 1988 (Box 51)
- "Undiplomatic History," draft by Durbrow,undated (Box 51)
- Durbrow oral history conducted by David Mabon for inclusion in the Foreign Relations of the United States, 1958-1960, Volume 1, Vietnam, photocopy, 1984 (Box 51)
- Memoir, drafts, undated. (Box 51)
  Includes handwritten version
- Durbrow oral history conducted by John T. Mason Jr. for the Columbia University Oral History project, draft transcripts and final transcript, 1981 (Box 51)
- "Taiwan Endangered," draft by Durbrow, 1985 (Box 51)
- "Toward a Balanced China Policy," by U. Alexis Johnson, circa 1984 (Box 51)
- "The United States Commitment to Taiwan's National Security," by Leonard Unger, 1984 (Box 51)
- "The 24th Soviet Communist Party Congress - An Assessment," by Durbrow (Box 51)
- Clippings, 1937, 1946, 1965, 1973, 1976, 1981, 1985-1989 (Box 52)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1963, 1970, 1978-1979, 1981, 1988, 1994 (Box 52)
  Includes correspondence with George Kennan and photocopies
- Printed material and photocopies, 1943, 1945, 1963, 1969, 1978, 1981, 1986-1987 (Box 52)
- U.S. government reports and press releases, 1956, 1971-1972, 1979, 1985-1986. (Box 52)
- The 20th Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union review report photocopy, 1956 (Box 52)
- Drafts by Durbrow, 1975, 1988 (Box 52)
  - "Can Gorbachev Pull It Off? Prospects,", 1988 (Box 52)
  - "Hot War, Cold War, and Détente - All Pay Well for the Kremlin,", 1975 (Box 52)
- "The Case of Harry Dexter White" by David Martin, undated (Box 52)
- "Chicago to Lisbon," chapter of memoir draft by Durbrow, 1940 (Box 52)
- "A Trip to Hevsuretia," by Durbrow, undated (Box 52)
- "To China, with Love," by Sheila K. Johnson, 1973 (Box 52)
- "Analysis of Church Committee Report," by Society of Former Special Agents of the FBI Inc. photocopy, 1977 (Box 52)
- Clippings, 1961, 1968-1969, 1972, 1978-1979 (Box 53)